<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-20T22:31:16-05:00</updated><id>http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/</id><title type="html">Tamouse’s Recipe File</title><subtitle>This is a collection of my personal and favourite recipes, collected over the years in various places.</subtitle><author><name>Tamara Temple</name></author><entry><title type="html">chicken curry rice</title><link href="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/05/20/chicken-curry-rice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="chicken curry rice" /><published>2020-05-20T22:21:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-20T22:21:00-05:00</updated><id>http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/05/20/chicken-curry-rice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/05/20/chicken-curry-rice.html">&lt;p&gt;I whipped this up pretty fast without looking anything up. It came out great with tons of leftovers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium onion, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6-8 boneless skinless chicken thighs, thawed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;seasoned salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;big pinch for each side: Raj al Hanout seasoning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12 oz jar Patek’s Curry Simmer Sauce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;peel and chop the onion, mince the garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;set IP to sauté. when hot, add the oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when the oil is hot, start sautéing the onions and garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;season one side of the thighs generously&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when onions are starting to turn translucent, push to the side, and lay the chicken in, seasoned side down&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;season the up side of the chicken generously&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;after 3 minutes, flip the chicken, and cook for another 3 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;remove all the chicken and onions, set aside&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;add 1 cup water to the pot, and set the trivet in&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;layer the chicken and onions on the trivet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pour over the jar of curry sauce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pour the rice over the top evenly, and press in to make sure nothing is high and dry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;set the IP to Pressure cook for 20 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when the pressure cycle is done, let natural release go for another 10-15 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;release the pressure, make sure everything is off, and pop the top&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if it’s too watery, remove the meat as best you can, and sauté the rice and sauce to reduce the liquid, stirring constantly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;shred the chicken so it’s in nice bite-sized pieces; don’t go too far&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when it’s to your desired thickness, add the meat back and give everything a good stir, and it’s ready to serve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Tamara Temple</name></author><category term="chicken" /><category term="curry" /><category term="rice" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="dairy-free" /><category term="instant-pot" /><summary type="html">I whipped this up pretty fast without looking anything up. It came out great with tons of leftovers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Zucchini and Summer Squash Pizza Crust</title><link href="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/pizza/2020/05/09/zucchini-and-summer-squash-pizza-crust.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zucchini and Summer Squash Pizza Crust" /><published>2020-05-09T06:31:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T06:31:00-05:00</updated><id>http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/pizza/2020/05/09/zucchini-and-summer-squash-pizza-crust</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/pizza/2020/05/09/zucchini-and-summer-squash-pizza-crust.html">&lt;p&gt;The source for this at allrecipes.com is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; dairy-free or gluten-free. &lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt; version is modified from that source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cups finely shredded zucchini or yellow summer squash (I used one each large zuc and squash)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 cup all-purpose gluten-free flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 cup cashew parmesean cheese (I use something called “Nooch”, but this is farely easy to make)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup nutritional yeast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup shredded dairy-free cheddar cheese (I used Daiya brand, there’s a few good ones out there. You can also use their mozzarella)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 eggs, beaten&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salt to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350 degrees F (175 degrees C).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re going to need 2 baking pans, with parchment paper lining for both of them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once zucchini or summer squash has been shredded (I recommend a food processor) lightly salt the zuch+squash and transfer it to a strainer. Let stand 15 to 30 minutes and press all remaining liquid out of squash.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium-sized mixing bowl, combine zuch+squash, flour, cashew cheese, dairy-free cheddar cheese, eggs, pepper and salt. Mix well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread the mixture into a baking sheet covered with parchment paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 25 minutes in the preheated oven.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the crust from the oven and change the oven’s temperature to broil. Brush the top of the crust with oil, and then broil the crust for 7 to 10 minutes until the top is lightly browned.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow the crust to cool slightly and slide spatula underneath all edges and under the middle. Place a larger, parchment-lined, baking pan over the top of the crust and gently flip the crust over so that the bottom of the crust is now facing upwards. (I laid the parchment sheet on top, then put the baking sheet on top of that to make things a little easier.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brush the top of the crust with oil and broil for another 7 to 10 minutes until the top is browned.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover with toppings as desired, such as veggies, more dairy-free cheese, etc. I put a light layer of tomato / spaghetti sauce, sliced onions, turkey pepperoni, and dairy-free shredded cheese.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Return to broiler for about 10-15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove pizza and transfer to a cutting board. Let rest for 10 minutes, cut into squares. Mine made 6 square slices, and was good for 3 servings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep time: 30 minutes, or more if draining takes longer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking time: 35 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: makes 6 good sized slices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calories: who knows??&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original recipe said this would take about an hour to cook. I found I had to extend the broiling times from 5 minutes to 10 minutes, even though I had moved the rack up near the broiler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to put a sauce on, do make sure to do the extra broiling to make the top crispier, and don’t pile on the sauce: keep it a thin, even coating&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This really is an awesome crust recipe, better than cauliflower crusts, or other sorts of GF crusts I’ve tried. This makes a chewy, delicious, faccacia type crust&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may have forgotten that I added some other spice things to crust to make it more interesting. I’ve been using paprika a lot this way. Also quite likely I dumped in some oregano and basil, it’d probably be great with some garlic powder / onion powder, too. Or maybe even fresh minced garlic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pictures&quot;&gt;Pictures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not a food photographer, these are just snaps from the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;raw-crust&quot;&gt;raw crust&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/recipes/img/2020-05-09-zucchini-and-summer-squash-pizza-crust/raw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;raw dough in pan&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;flipped&quot;&gt;flipped&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I flipped it over&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/recipes/img/2020-05-09-zucchini-and-summer-squash-pizza-crust/flipped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;crust flipped over for second broil&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;top-broiled&quot;&gt;top-broiled&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready for toppings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/recipes/img/2020-05-09-zucchini-and-summer-squash-pizza-crust/top-broiled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Top broiled to perfection&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;smothered-in-toppings&quot;&gt;smothered in toppings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/recipes/img/2020-05-09-zucchini-and-summer-squash-pizza-crust/topped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pizza topped with extra stuff&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tamara Temple</name></author><category term="pizza-crust" /><category term="veggie" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="dairy-free" /><summary type="html">The source for this at allrecipes.com is not dairy-free or gluten-free. This version is modified from that source.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Shrimp Stir Fry with Rice In It</title><link href="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/05/04/shrimp-stir-fry-with-rice-in-it.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shrimp Stir Fry with Rice In It" /><published>2020-05-04T22:25:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T22:25:00-05:00</updated><id>http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/05/04/shrimp-stir-fry-with-rice-in-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/05/04/shrimp-stir-fry-with-rice-in-it.html">&lt;p&gt;Made this a couple of night ago, yet another of what my sister calls “Stuff with Stuff In It” :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order of appearance, mainly, but you want to spend a bit of time prepping and getting everything together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium yellow onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 stalks celery, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;half a left-over bag of brussels sprouts (about 10 or so on the smaller side), diced up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a double handful of cole slaw mix (green and red cabbage, julliened carrots), chop it up a bit so there aren’t any massive bits of cabbage heart&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;another 1/2 cup or so of left-over shredded carrots&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a heaping tablespoon of minced garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a heaping tablespoon of crushed ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 microwave pouch of brown and wild rice (you &lt;strong&gt;have&lt;/strong&gt; to check these for allergens when you’re shopping!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;chinese five spice powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;curry powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;seasoned salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tamari or braggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sesame oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rice vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a tablespoon of tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a tiny bit of thai chili garlic paste (how much you use is entirely your business)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;about 20 frozen shrimp, shelled and deveined, but not yet cooked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;heat up a big skillet, put a little oil in it, use whatever you like&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dump the onion, celery, sprouts, cole slaw mix, and carrots in the pan, and give it a good 4-5 minutes to get going, stirring it up occasionally&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;add the garlic and ginger, get that going well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;add the dry spices and mix them in well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;add the tamari, sesame oil, rice vinegar, tomato paste, and chili paste, mix that in well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cook the rice while letting the pan stuff continue to meld&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;give the frozen shrimp a minute or two in the microwave to get the ice off, drain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;make a little space for the shrimp in the pan, put them in cook, covering with the rest of the ingredients&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;after a couple minutes, turn the shrimps so they cook on both sides&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dump in the rice and mix everything together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prepped all the veggies up to the carrots and just dumped them in a big bowl. After the pan and oil were hot enough, I dumped the bowl right in. I’ve made the mistake of starting cooking some of the ingredients while still prepping the others, and that ended up not so well. Also pull out all the dry and wet spices so you have those ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have measures for the seasoning, because that’s really your business. I never measure, just put in enough until it looks good. I may have put in a bit too much 5 spice, but I’m okay with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stir fries don’t take constant attention in my experience when you’re cooking on a standard stove in a standard skillet. If you have a wok and a high flame, you have to pay a lot more attention to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 90-second rice pouches: I use these a lot, but one has to read labels on them. Sometimes they include soy, wheat, milk, nuts, and so on. If you’re good, you can make your own rice and stand in the light of your own righteous cooking skills. You can also do cauliflower rice, or quinoa, or even pasta. I’m not the boss of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feeds me for three meals easily. I mean, if you had to do four, you’d still be getting a big bowl of goodness.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tamara Temple</name></author><category term="shrimp" /><category term="rice" /><category term="garlic" /><category term="onions" /><category term="ginger" /><category term="dairy-free" /><category term="glutten-free" /><summary type="html">Made this a couple of night ago, yet another of what my sister calls “Stuff with Stuff In It” :D</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Roasted Veggies and Keilbasa</title><link href="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/03/18/roasted-veggies-and-keilbasa.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Roasted Veggies and Keilbasa" /><published>2020-03-18T23:23:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-18T23:23:00-05:00</updated><id>http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/03/18/roasted-veggies-and-keilbasa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/03/18/roasted-veggies-and-keilbasa.html">&lt;div id=&quot;roasted-veggies-and-keilbasa&quot; class=&quot;recipe_entry&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p id=&quot;excerpt&quot;&gt;This was a quick toss-together recipe and so very tasty. Freezes well.&lt;/p&gt;

  
  &lt;h3&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;cup&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;water&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;cup&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;baby carrots&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;cup&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;small yukon gold potatoes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;; large dice&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;large&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;onion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;; large dice&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;pound&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;frozen broccoli florets&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;Tbsp&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;olive oil&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;Tbsp&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;sesame oil&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;Tbsp&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;balsamic vinegar&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;
  
  
  &lt;span&gt;salt and pepper&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;ring&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;keilbasa&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;; sliced into 1/4 inch slices about 1/8 inch thick&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  

  
  &lt;h3&gt;Direcctions&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;turn on the oven to 450&amp;deg;F to let it preheat&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;prep a baking sheet by lining it with foil&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;place water in bottom of instant pot liner&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;place wire trivet into liner&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;place steaming basket on trivet&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;dump carrots and potatoes into steaming basket&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;set for pressure cook, 10 minutes, high.&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;after pressure time is done, use quick release (vent the steam)&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;cool the veggies under cold water until you can handle them&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;place all else except keilbasa in a large ziplock, and shake it up to mix it&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;pour out the veggies onto the foiled baking sheet&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;arrange the slices of keilbasa evenly over the top&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;roast at 450&amp;deg;F for approximately 25 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
    
    &lt;li&gt;eat them veggies, freezes really well&lt;/li&gt;
    
  &lt;/ol&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Tamara Temple</name></author><category term="veggies" /><category term="roasted-veggies" /><category term="keilbasa" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="dairy-free" /><category term="instant-pot" /><summary type="html">This was a quick toss-together recipe and so very tasty. Freezes well. Ingredients 1 cup water 1 cup baby carrots 1 cup small yukon gold potatoes; large dice 1 large onion; large dice 1 pound frozen broccoli florets 2 Tbsp olive oil 1 Tbsp sesame oil 2 Tbsp balsamic vinegar salt and pepper 1 ring keilbasa; sliced into 1/4 inch slices about 1/8 inch thick Direcctions turn on the oven to 450&amp;deg;F to let it preheat prep a baking sheet by lining it with foil place water in bottom of instant pot liner place wire trivet into liner place steaming basket on trivet dump carrots and potatoes into steaming basket set for pressure cook, 10 minutes, high. after pressure time is done, use quick release (vent the steam) cool the veggies under cold water until you can handle them place all else except keilbasa in a large ziplock, and shake it up to mix it pour out the veggies onto the foiled baking sheet arrange the slices of keilbasa evenly over the top roast at 450&amp;deg;F for approximately 25 minutes eat them veggies, freezes really well</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Paprika Potatoes &amp;amp; Onions</title><link href="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/side-dishes/2020/02/02/paprika-potatoes-and-onions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paprika Potatoes &amp; Onions" /><published>2020-02-02T20:38:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-02-02T20:38:00-06:00</updated><id>http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/side-dishes/2020/02/02/paprika-potatoes-and-onions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/side-dishes/2020/02/02/paprika-potatoes-and-onions.html">&lt;p&gt;Potatoes are a common appetizer in Spain, in small plates known as tapas, often served with garlic aioli sauce or spicy bravas sauce. Potatoes can also be found in a tortilla, a Spanish version of an omelet, with sweet onions. I love the flavors of garlic and paprika from the aioli and bravas sauces. Potatoes with onions are another winning combination. Combining all of these elements makes for a delicious dish. Paprika potatoes with onions are perfect for breakfast, lunch or dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Gluten-Free Living magazine, Naturally Gluten-Free, “Welcome to a world of flavor” by Jennifer Fitzpatrick, March/April 2020 issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pound multi-color or rainbow fingerling potatoes, cut into large chunks or quartered&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Spanish onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoon olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 teaspoons garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon paprika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt and fresh ground pepper, to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 425 ° F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Line two baking sheets or jelly roll pans with foil or a silicone baking mat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peel and cut the onion into large chunks, making sure both the potatoes and onions are roughly the same size. This will allow them to cook evenly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the onions and potatoes into a bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 1 tablespoon olive oil, and use your hands to make sure the oil is coated on all the potato and onion pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the garlic powder, paprika, and salt and pepper to taste.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toss again and pour onto baking sheet, distributing evenly and leaving space.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roast the potato and onion mixture in the oven for 10-12 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove and use a spatula to move the mixture around.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coat again with another tablespoon of olive oil, toss and return to oven for an additional 10-12 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove potatoes and onions or bake until desired crispness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dish can also be prepared in a frying pan on the stovetop over medium heat.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tamara Temple</name></author><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="dairy-free" /><category term="potatoes" /><category term="onions" /><category term="paprika" /><category term="roasted" /><summary type="html">Potatoes are a common appetizer in Spain, in small plates known as tapas, often served with garlic aioli sauce or spicy bravas sauce. Potatoes can also be found in a tortilla, a Spanish version of an omelet, with sweet onions. I love the flavors of garlic and paprika from the aioli and bravas sauces. Potatoes with onions are another winning combination. Combining all of these elements makes for a delicious dish. Paprika potatoes with onions are perfect for breakfast, lunch or dinner.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One-Pan Egg Roll</title><link href="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/02/02/one-pan-egg-roll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One-Pan Egg Roll" /><published>2020-02-02T20:28:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-02-02T20:28:00-06:00</updated><id>http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/02/02/one-pan-egg-roll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/02/02/one-pan-egg-roll.html">&lt;p&gt;Craving the classic flavors of an egg roll but without the wrapper? This one-pan version is an incredibly simple meal that’s made with a variety of vegetables and tastes just like a traditional egg roll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pound (454 g) ground pork&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon sea salt, divided&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons (28 g) coconut oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 white onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 garlic clove, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons grated peeled fresh ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup (110 g) shredded carrot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 heads baby bok choy, base trimmed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium head green cabbage, shredded&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup (96 g) mushrooms, sliced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons (45 ml) coconut aminos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons (12 g) chopped scallion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large skillet over medium heat, combine the ground pork and 3/4 teaspoon of salt. Cook for 7 to 8 minutes, or until browned, breaking up the meat with the back of a spoon. Remove from the skillet and set aside. Discard the fat and return the skillet to medium heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the coconut oil to the skillet to melt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the onion, garlic, and ginger and sauté for 5 to 6 minutes, or until the onion is translucent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the carrot and sauté for 2 to 3 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the bok choy, cabbage, and mushroom and stir to combine.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir in the vinegar, coconut aminos, and remaining ¼ teaspoon of salt. Cook, stirring, for 4 to 5 minutes to cook down the cabbage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir in the pork and cook for 1 minute more, or until warmed. Remove from heat and serve warm topped with the scallion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking time: 25 min&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Tamara Temple</name></author><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="dairy-free" /><category term="simple" /><category term="asian" /><summary type="html">Craving the classic flavors of an egg roll but without the wrapper? This one-pan version is an incredibly simple meal that’s made with a variety of vegetables and tastes just like a traditional egg roll.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Instant Pot Chicken Burrito Bowls</title><link href="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/01/02/instant-pot-shredded-chicken-burrito-bowls.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Instant Pot Chicken Burrito Bowls" /><published>2020-01-02T01:57:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-01-02T01:57:00-06:00</updated><id>http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/01/02/instant-pot-shredded-chicken-burrito-bowls</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2020/01/02/instant-pot-shredded-chicken-burrito-bowls.html">&lt;p&gt;From the webiste: “Instant Pot &lt;del&gt;Shredded&lt;/del&gt; Chicken Burrito Bowl is the most delicious Burrito you will ever eat. One pot cooking in your instant pot and it takes less than 20 minutes to prepare.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prep Time: 4 min&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook Time: 30 min (8 minutes pressure, 20 minutes standing slow release, coupla minutes slop)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serves: 8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 (not 3) boneless, skinless chicken &lt;del&gt;breasts&lt;/del&gt; thighs (using chicken thighs, boneless, skinless, figuring 1 breast is about 2 thighs, more or less) &lt;em&gt;cut up, because I’m not shredding it&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 1/4 cups of chicken broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pack of taco seasoning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 can of sweet corn, drained&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 can of black beans, rinsed and drained&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 can of Rotel (tomatoes, small dice, seasoned okay)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;1 medium green bell pepper, sliced (left out)&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;1 medium red bell pepper, sliced (left out)&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium onion, sliced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 small can roasted mild green chilis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups of long grain rice (I only had 1 cup of long grain, and used a “Royal Mix” of Texmati, Jasmine, Red, and Wild rices - it worked well)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preparation-steps&quot;&gt;Preparation Steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the Instant Pot, pour just enough chicken broth to cover the bottom of the pot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then place the chicken along the bottom of the pot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sprinkle the taco seasoning evenly over the chicken.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour the corn, black beans, and tomatoes into the pot. Try to pour them in different sections of the pot, so everything doesn’t pile up in one place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the sliced onions and the green chilis, spreading them evenly along the top, so they don’t pile up too much.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the rice evenly to the pot, then add the remaining chicken broth. Try to push the rice down so that it’s covered by the broth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using your Instant Pot’s instructions, pressure cook for 8 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once it’s done cooking, allow it to slowly depressurize for 20 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then release the sealing valve to vent any remaining pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Remove the lid. Using 2 forks pull the chicken meat apart so it becomes thin enough for a good taco consistency. (This feels a little dangerous in terms of heat. Might remove the chicken pieces to a bowl to do the shredding, then add back. Put the lid back on and seal it while shredding the chicken outside the bowl.)&lt;/del&gt; Cutting up the chicken worked fine.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stir well to incorporate all the ingredients &lt;del&gt;and place the lid back on&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Do not turn the Instant Pot on, but let it sit with the lid sealed for at least 5 minutes. This will finish cooking any rice that may have been sitting on the top and not cooked all the way through.&lt;/del&gt; completely unnecessary with step 8 above&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy in a bowl by itself, in a soft tortilla, or with tortilla chips. And don’t forget your favorite toppings!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;toppings&quot;&gt;Toppings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;had&quot;&gt;had:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pico de gallo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;shredded cheddar non-dairy cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-try&quot;&gt;to try:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;guac&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salsa&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;corn tortilla chips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Tamara Temple</name></author><category term="instant-pot" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="dairy-free" /><category term="chicken" /><category term="beans" /><category term="corn" /><category term="rice" /><category term="tomatoes" /><summary type="html">From the webiste: “Instant Pot Shredded Chicken Burrito Bowl is the most delicious Burrito you will ever eat. One pot cooking in your instant pot and it takes less than 20 minutes to prepare.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gyros Meat</title><link href="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2019/11/19/gyros-meat.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gyros Meat" /><published>2019-11-19T18:50:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-11-19T18:50:00-06:00</updated><id>http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2019/11/19/gyros-meat</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/main-dishes/2019/11/19/gyros-meat.html">&lt;p&gt;This sounds quite easy to make one of my favourite things to eat. Can also use with ground pork or chicken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 onion, cut into chunks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pound ground lamb&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pound ground beef&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon minced garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon dried marjoram&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon ground dried rosemary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon ground dried thyme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 teaspoon sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prep-meat-mixture&quot;&gt;Prep meat mixture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the onion in a food processor, and process until finely chopped.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scoop the onions onto the center of a towel, gather up the ends of the towel, and squeeze out the liquid from the onions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the onions into a mixing bowl along with the lamb and beef.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Season with the garlic, oregano, cumin, marjoram, rosemary, thyme, black pepper, and salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix well with your hands until well combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover, and refrigerate 1 to 2 hours to allow the flavors to blend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cook-meat-loaf&quot;&gt;Cook meat loaf&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 325 degrees F (165 degrees C).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the meat mixture into the food processor, and pulse for about a minute until finely chopped and the mixture feels tacky.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pack the meat mixture into a 7x4 inch loaf pan, making sure there are no air pockets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Line a roasting pan with a damp kitchen towel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the loaf pan on the towel, inside the roasting pan, and place into the preheated oven.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fill the roasting pan with boiling water to reach halfway up the sides of the loaf pan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake until the gyro meat is no longer pink in the center, and the internal temperature registers 165 degrees F (75 degrees C) on a meat thermometer, 45 minutes to 1 hour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour off any accumulated fat, and allow to cool slightly before slicing thinly and serving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Tamara Temple</name></author><category term="greek" /><category term="beef" /><category term="lamb" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="dairy-free" /><summary type="html">This sounds quite easy to make one of my favourite things to eat. Can also use with ground pork or chicken.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Slow Cooker Butternut Squash Soup</title><link href="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/soups/2019/11/17/slow-cooker-butternut-squash-soup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Slow Cooker Butternut Squash Soup" /><published>2019-11-17T14:24:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-11-17T14:24:00-06:00</updated><id>http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/soups/2019/11/17/slow-cooker-butternut-squash-soup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/soups/2019/11/17/slow-cooker-butternut-squash-soup.html">&lt;p&gt;A pretty simple, classic slow-cooker version, modified to be gluten-free and dairy-free, and to fit my needs for preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;14oz package frozen butternut squash cubes, thawed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 carrots, peeled and cut into chunks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium yellow onion, quartered&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 potato, peeled and cut into chunks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pint chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 bay leaf&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon ground nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salt and ground black pepper to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat oven to 500°F&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Line a baking pan with foil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread squash, carrots, and onion out into a single layer on the prepared baking pan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake in the preheated oven until slightly browned, about 10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour roasted squash pieces, carrots, onions, and potato into slow cooker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour chicken stock over vegetables and stir in bay leaf, garlic powder, nutmeg, salt, and black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook on High for 4 hours, stirring once&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DISCARD BAY LEAF before puréing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Purée soup with an immersion blender until smooth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not so precise on the amount of squash I used. I had a 10oz package so that’s what I used. I thawed in the microwave before adding it to the other vegetables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added oil and salt to the vegetables mix before putting it on the pan to roast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 minutes was not enough time to lightly brown the vegetables.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tamara Temple</name></author><category term="soup" /><category term="slow-cooker" /><category term="butternut-squash" /><category term="carrots" /><category term="onions" /><category term="potatoes" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="dairy-free" /><summary type="html">A pretty simple, classic slow-cooker version, modified to be gluten-free and dairy-free, and to fit my needs for preparation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Preparing Eggplant for Casseroles</title><link href="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/kitchen-tips/2019/11/09/prepping-eggplant-for-casseroles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Preparing Eggplant for Casseroles" /><published>2019-11-09T12:26:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-11-09T12:26:00-06:00</updated><id>http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/kitchen-tips/2019/11/09/prepping-eggplant-for-casseroles</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tamouse.github.io//recipes/kitchen-tips/2019/11/09/prepping-eggplant-for-casseroles.html">&lt;p&gt;Eggplant, especially the large European variety, contain a lot of moisture; unless you’re frying the eggplant slices before using them, they need some prep work to be good in casseroles and bakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 pounds eggplant (1 large or 2 small)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;kosher or coarse (sea) salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat the oven to 450°F&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spray a baking sheet with oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trim the ends off the eggplant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slice into 1/4 inch slices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arrange slices on the prepared baking sheet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Season with the salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake 10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flip pieces over&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake another 10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The eggplant should be golden brown.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tamara Temple</name></author><category term="eggplant" /><summary type="html">Eggplant, especially the large European variety, contain a lot of moisture; unless you’re frying the eggplant slices before using them, they need some prep work to be good in casseroles and bakes.</summary></entry></feed>